what's up my friend David Moss Jr here
and in this video we're going to be
doing a review of a protein this is
momentous grass-fed whey protein isolate
we're also going to be talking about
momentus collagen peptides these are two
different types of protein that you can
and possibly should be taking on a daily
basis but we're going to figure that out
and we're going to talk about what goes
into both of these proteins and if it's
a supplement worth you considering or
not let's Jump Right In so before we
jump into the supplement itself let's
talk about protein yes protein is
something that we should get from our
daily diet but so many of this miss the
boat and we don't get the amount that we
actually need to be optimized and
protein itself is a fundamental
macronutrient and it's really a critical
building block of the human body it's
essential for the growth development and
recovery of our muscles I'm not a
scientist I'm not a doctor but it seems
to be a fact that when I include more
protein in my diet I look better I feel
better and I perform better and I'm sure
you probably agree with me when you
include more protein in your diet and
you work out on a regular basis you feel
better you have more energy and you look
better right so now let's jump into the
moment grass-fed whey protein and see if
this is the right protein for you so to
me I eat a lot of red meat but when it
comes down to choosing the right whey
protein I want to know exactly where the
whey protein is coming from and one of
the things I love about momentus is that
they actually list everything on their
website so I'm going to pop a link down
in the description below that you're
more than welcome to check out yes I do
have a discount code you're more than
welcome to use as well if you do decide
to get any product with moment is the
discount code is moss so feel free to
use that after this video but let's talk
about where the grass-fed way protein
from momentus actually comes from what I
found out is that they've actually
collaborated with registered dietitians
and Human Performance Specialists with
the mindset of creating the top quality
NSF certified protein that athletes in
anybody with longevity in mind can take
it's sourced from European Dairy Farmers
who are held to much higher standards
unfortunately than us here in America
and the way protein iset comes from
grass-fed dairy cows it's cold processed
to preserve the native protein
structures which is awesome and they
also include prohydrolase which is going
to help with digestion and Max
absorption and all that stuff's
important but personally to me what I
love is the Taste and the mixability if
that's a word I truly don't like to use
those Shaker bottles with the little
blender ball because my kids like to
play with them and we lose them but I do
like to put protein in a bottle shake it
up and be able to just drink it and this
mixes really really well without using a
blender or having to use one of those
blender bottles plus it tastes great
currently momentus has three flavors one
is unflavored the second which is my
favorite is chocolate and the third is
vanilla there might be more flavors
coming out in the future but for now
those are the three you can choose from
let's take a quick look at the
supplemental facts with each serving you
get 100 calories only 1.5 G of fat 3 G
of carbs and a full 22.2 G of grass-fed
whey protein isolate another thing I
really like is that they put a breakdown
of the entire complex of amino acids
that come in each scoop so you know
exactly what you're getting per serving
of amino acids and for those of you who
are super nerdy like me and really
curious you get 200 Mig of proh hydroly
and 2.2 G of Lucine per serving now
let's dive into collagen peptides so I
think we can all agree that having a
good quality grass-fed whe Protein
Isolate like moment is is a good idea
but let's go ahead and talk about
collagen collagen is actually the most
abundant protein in the entire body and
what's crazy about collagen is it's
vital in the structure of your tendons
your ligaments your bones your eyes your
skin and your muscles and the problem we
face is so many people just eat muscle
meat which is great but collagen became
important when we realized that people
especially in America aren't eating nose
to tail we're not eating the entire
animal we're really just eating the
muscle meat which is a great source of
protein but most of the collagen that
we're supposed to get from our daily
diet would come from a nose to tail diet
eating more than just the muscle Meats
from an animal but now let's dive a
little bit deeper into the momentous
collagen surprisingly there's a lot to
talk about when it comes to the collagen
made by momentus and I'm a huge collagen
fan but I've never seen anything quite
like this not only is collagen the most
abundant form of protein in our body
it's found in like literally every part
of our body anything that's connective
it's also super important for the
regrowth of our cartilage and Mobility
it helps us become a little bit more
elastic collagen is critical in
supporting the Health and Longevity of
our extracellular Matrix which is the
critical network of proteins and
molecules that support a healthy
cellular growth and development super
important for kids but even more
important for adults and the elderly
along with bovine collagen they've also
put vitamin C and they've even added
fora gel to create an easy mixing powder
that provides 16.8 G of collagen
peptides that supports types 1 2 and
three collagen in the body if you don't
know what fortigel is fortigel is a
hydrolyzed form of collagen broken down
into smaller peptides to increase the
maximum absorption of the coll collagen
now let's break down the supplemental
facts of the collagen peptides each
serving is going to give you 60 calories
you're going to get 50 Mig of vitamin C
which is really cool 11 G of collagen
peptide and 5.2 G of forel collagen
hydrate the collagen is unflavored so
you can put this in literally anything I
like to put it in my coffee personally
but a lot of times also throw it in my
protein shake as well so I can really
double down on the good protein sources
that my body needs a few last remarks
about momentus as a supplement company
is their NSF certified for sport which
is awesome so if you're a professional
athlete it's certified for sport you can
actually take the supplements which are
great which to anybody else means
they're extremely rigorously tested by
third party sources to make sure that
what you're paying for is exactly what
you're getting and it comes from
reliable sources now I'm a huge fan of
momentus I hope you are too after this
video If you want to get some
supplements for yourself check out the
link down in the description below I'll
see you guys on the next video have a
great day and God bless hey before you
go if you really enjoy a good quality
supplement I want you to check out this
video next this is a really cool video
on a supplement I think you're probably
deficient in because over 90% of the
American population is so check this
video out right here on magnesium I
think you're going to like it